字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
EPISODE 3: TROLL
第三集：巨怪
There are no major changes.
没什么大变化
Compensation is five pounds of gold.
报酬是4.5斤黄金
You won't be paid until you produce the body.
只有他的尸体被确认后 你才会拿到报酬
You may do what you wish with his ships and cargo.
至于他的船和货物 随你处置
Kill Thors.
杀掉托尔兹
-Come on! I told you, monk! -I'm next!
-快点！我告诉过你的 僧人 -接下去是我
Thors, eh?
托尔兹啊？
The Troll of Jom.
“约姆的巨怪”
I've heard of him. But are you sure? Is he not a hero in your land?
我听说过他
I wouldn't ask you to kill him if he was a hero.
如果他真的是英雄 我是不会让你去杀他的
He broke a military law. Desertion in the face of the enemy.
他严重触犯了军法 直接冒犯军队
The order for his execution has stood for 15 years.
处死他的命令已经存在了15年
I know you're one for upholding the law but, my God, 15 years?
我知道你极为看重法律的维护
You took your time.
你们干得可真够慢的
But, I mean,
不 我的意思是
as long as I'm paid properly, I'll take any job given to me.
只要付足够的钱 我就会完成任务
But you know,
但你也知道
when you're executing one of your own, I thought normally you'd do it yourself.
我以为你们杀自己人的时候 总是会自己动手的
You went to Iceland, didn't you?
你去了冰岛 对吧？
Why didn't you kill him then?
那时候为什么没杀掉他？
The Christian monk's already dead.
哦 这个基督僧侣已经死了
That's not your concern.
这和你无关
For your own sake, keep your nose out of it.
为你自己好 你最好别管
Fine by me.
那行吧
Give me five more pounds of gold in advance and I'll take the job.
事先再给我4.5斤黄金
It's bold of you to ask for that so casually.
你这么随随便便地提要求 很大胆啊
Oh, no! Sorry about that.
哦 不 抱歉
It just slipped out of my hand. No one's hurt, right?
不小心从我手里滑出去了 没人受伤吧？
You must be more careful!
嘿 小心点！
You could have hit me!
你差一点打到我！
-You're awful at it! -You're drinking too much, Bjorn!
-你很不擅长这个！ -你喝太多了 表伦！
Another five pounds of gold in advance.
事先再给4.5斤黄金
Then we'll do it.
那么我们就去干
Fine.
好吧
You're as manly as I expected. I'll see you later then.
你果然如预料的一样有气魄
By the way.
哦 顺便问一下
What kind of warrior is this Thors?
托尔兹是哪种战士？
How does he look?
他是怎么观察又怎么战斗的？
Thors is no longer a warrior.
托尔兹已经不再是战士了
All right, drinking game is over. Time to get to work, you rogues.
行了 不要再喝了！
Bjorn, that was a good throw.
表伦 扔得不错啊
No sweat.
小菜一碟
Even caught Floki off guard.
哪怕是佛洛基都大吃一惊
I wish I could have seen his face.
要是我能看到他脸上的表情就好了
Seems he's not just idle talk.
他看起来是言而有信的人
For me, Ari, son of Geitr, the time has come to become a man.
我 亚雷 盖特之子 到了我成为男人的时候了
I know. Don't say a word. Of course, it won't be an easy journey.
我知道 你什么都不用说
And it is possible I'll be injured on the field of battle.
也不能保证我在战场上不会受伤
But I shall return home!
但我一定会回到家！
And when I do, I will present you with a necklace plundered from England!
等我回来的时候 我会为你带一条从英格兰夺来的项链
-I'm still sleepy. -Now, if you would…
-你知道么 我困着呢 -那个时候 如果你愿意
m… ma… marr…
嫁…嫁过…嫁过来
-Marry-- -Ari!
-嫁给我… -亚雷！
Your lunch. You forgot your lunch.
你把你的午餐忘了
Mother!
妈妈！
Why are you so careless? Be sure to share the salted herring with the others.
你怎么这么不小心呢？
-I made a lot. -Move it, Mother.
-我做了很多 -妈妈 你去那边
How dare you speak to me that way!
你怎么能这么对你妈妈说话呢！
I'll talk to you when I return. Wait for me, Ylva!
等我回来了再跟你说
They're leaving today.
他们今天就走…
I hope they don't die.
希望他们不会死
Ylva.
攸尔法
Could I have a word?
我能跟你说几句话吗？
Wait, I'm first!
等等 我先说
Hey, Ylva!
嘿 攸尔法
Maybe try somewhere else?
能麻烦你们到别的地方去吗？
Don't forget to wash properly every Saturday, dear?
宝贝 一定记得周六要好好洗澡
Yes, Mama.
知道了 妈妈
I swear on the axe of my ancestors to bring back a chest of gold coins!
我向我祖先的斧头发誓 一定会带回来一大桶金币！
The young men are in high spirits!
这帮年轻人真是斗志高昂！
But are only five men really enough?
但五个人是不是太少了？
Thors said that five was enough.
托尔兹说五个人足够了
Well, if he says so, then it must be right.
如果他这么说的话 那一定可以
But five men are barely enough to sail the ship.
但五个人刚刚够推动船
But if that's what he decided, he must have a good reason.
既然是托尔兹决定的 那一定有原因
What were you talking about with Ylva?
嘿 你和攸尔法说什么了？
Shut up, you dope. I could ask you the same thing.
闭嘴 你个蠢货 我也能问你相同问题
You better watch your back on the battlefield.
战场上你最好小心你身后
Don't mock me. I could say the same to you.
别小瞧我 这话该我对你说
Ari!
亚雷
What?
怎么？
Be careful out there.
在外面小心点
Yeah.
哦
-We're not done here. -What did you say?
我跟你还没说完
Don't walk in front of me!
别走在我前面
Miss.
小姐
Are you worried about Ari?
你是担心亚雷吗？
Then let me tell you a secret.
那我跟你说个秘密
What? They're not going off to war?
什么？他们不是要上战场？
It's a secret.
这是个秘密
On our way to Jomsborg, we'll stop in Norway.
在去约姆斯堡的路上 我们会在挪威停一下
There, Thors plans to leave those boys behind.
托尔兹打算把这些小伙子留在那里
With new sailors from Norway, Thors will set off to Jomsborg.
等挪威的新船员上来后 托尔兹再去约姆斯堡
I'm a friend of the former king of Norway.
我和挪威前国王是朋友
I've got some influence there.
在那里我有一些影响力
And as soon as I'm done trading, I'll bring those boys home.
等我做完了交易 就会把这些小伙子们带回家
I can only carry about five men on my rotting old boat.
我锈迹斑斑的旧船只能带大概五个人
Thors won't take a single one of them into battle.
托尔兹不会带他们中任何一个上战场
That's the kind of man Thors is.
托尔兹就是这样的男人
Thorfinn!
托尔芬！
Hey! Where are you?
嘿 你在哪里？
But Leif.
可是 雷夫
Does that mean Thors will go to battle alone?
这是不是说托尔兹会独自上战场？
Ready to sail!
准备起航！
What's with that oar?
那个大船桨是怎么回事？
That Thorfinn. How could he not see Father off?
那个托尔芬真是的 怎么能不跟父亲告别呢？
Is he still holding a grudge about last night?
他还在为昨晚生气吗？
-Helga! -Yes?
-赫尔加 -怎么？
Tell Thorfinn for me…
帮我告诉托尔芬…
that… well…
那个…这…
I mean…
我是说…
Yes. I will tell him.
好的 我会告诉他的
Thank you.
谢谢
All right. Depart!
好了 起航了！
What monstrous strength.
这是多么可怕的力量啊…
Idiot! Don't stop rowing!
笨蛋 别停止划船！
Paddle!
快划桨！
Good luck!
祝好运！
Bring back trophies!
要带纪念品回来！
Open the sail!
挂帆！
-The skin on my hands is raw. -Oh, my butt!
我手上的皮肤都起泡了
Hang in there.
嘿 要坚持住
Ari, man the rudder.
亚雷 你来掌舵
Mord and Magni, adjust the buntlines. Hakon and Grim, do the braces.
莫德和马格尼 调整一下拢帆索
Are you tired?
你累了吗？
No, not at all…
不 一点都不…
Don't worry. There's not much rowing from here.
别担心 这里不怎么需要划桨
We're in the current, so it'll move on its own.
我们能跟着水流前进 所以会自己动
Does that mean we can't turn back, Father?
父亲 这是不是说 我们现在已经回不了头了？
You could say that.
我想你可以这么说吧
"Father"?
“父亲”？
Tho--
托尔…
Thorfinn! You--
托尔芬！你…
Not now!
现在不行
Made it.
终于可以了…
You sneaky little--
你这个鬼鬼祟祟的小…
Father!
父亲！
The sea!
大海！
There's something suspicious about this.
这事情有点可疑
What's that?
为什么？
That Floki is hiding many things.
佛洛基隐瞒了很多事情
What he said about Thors's execution must be a lie.
他说的托尔兹的处决令肯定是谎言
I'm sure of it.
我肯定
Then what is this?
那这什么情况？
An assassination.
暗杀
I don't know if it's personal, but he decided this on his own.
我不知道这是私人恩怨还是别的什么 但这是他自己的决定
So what?
那又怎样？
We still get paid if we kill him.
反正我们杀了他就有钱赚
Why do you think he didn't use his own men?
你说 他为何不让自己的人去干呢？
So he's not caught violating orders?
因为他不想因违抗命令而惹麻烦？
Well, that's part of it.
那可能是原因之一
But perhaps he's afraid of what he might lose.
但也可能他是担心自己会损失的东西
A loss so great, he can't explain it to his leader.
这个损失大到他无法向他上级交代
Like losing an entire Jomsvikings crew?
比如整个约姆战士团的人？
To get one old warrior?
就因为要杀一个老战士？
That's ridiculous.
这太可笑了
Get down here, you brat!
嘿 你个小孩 快下来！
Suddenly, I want to see this Troll of Jom for myself.
忽然 我就想看看这个约姆的巨怪
I'm glad that he'll provide some excitement.
我很高兴他能成为我的消遣
I can't see any stars. I can't see anything.
我看不到任何星星 看不到任何东西
Which way are we going?
我们要往哪里走？
Thors!
托尔兹！
The wind has changed! A little to the right.
风向变了！偏右一点
I will take the lead. Follow behind me.
我来带头 跟着我
All right!
好的！
Wow.
哇
How is Leif able to navigate the sea without getting lost?
雷夫是怎么在海中航行而不迷路的？
Ari.
亚雷
Don't stare long into the night sea.
别盯着晚上的海看太久
It will drag you under.
它会把你吞噬进去
Thors.
嘿 托尔兹
What's the battlefield like?
战场是怎么样的？
You've fought all over, haven't you?
你都打过的 对吧？
Tell me some of your great stories.
跟我说说你最棒的故事
I want to take down an enemy leader and become a man too!
我也想杀死敌人的首领 成为一个真正的男人
I see.
这样啊
My daughter certainly prefers strong men.
我的女儿确实喜欢强壮的男人
It'll be tough for you too.
对你来说 这也是很难的
You got me. You saw right through me.
被你看出来了 你一眼就看穿我
Do you like Ylva, Ari?
亚雷 你喜欢攸尔法吗？
Yeah, she's my type. She's cute.
是的 她就是我喜欢的类型 很可爱
She was born when I was still a Jomsviking.
她出生的时候 我还在约姆战士团
She's my first child.
她是我第一个孩子
She's noisy.
她很吵
Do all babies cry this much?
所有婴儿都哭这么多吗？
Thors, you mustn't hold her like that!
托尔兹 你不能这么抱她
Support her head!
要支撑她的头
Give me a boy next time, Helga.
赫尔加 下一次给我生个男孩
The leader wishes for a boy.
首领想要个男孩
My wife Helga is the daughter of the army leader.
我的妻子赫尔加是军队首领的女儿
Her face was pale after a difficult labor.
生产后 她脸色苍白
Thors.
托尔兹
Give her a name.
给她取个名吧
Name her what you like.
随便你叫她什么
I'm busy.
我很忙
The Norway campaign is soon.
挪威战役很快就要开始了
Thors, the ships are leaving.
托尔兹 舰队要出发了
Good. I'll go now.
好的 我现在就走
Thors!
托尔兹！
Give her a name.
给她取个名
In the 15 years we've been together,
我们在一起这15年里
Helga has only been angry that one time.
赫尔加就只生气过那一次
Ylva was the name of my mother.
攸尔法是我母亲的名字
It just came to me.
我忽然就想到的
Now that I think about it, that's when it started.
现在想想 一切就是从那时开始的
That's when I began to fear the battlefield.
正是那时起 我开始害怕战场
That is why I fled.
所以我逃走了
The warriors who knew me then may speak ill of me now.
那时候认识我的战士们 现在可能会说我的坏话
Hey! I can see the Faroe Islands!
嘿 我能看到法罗群岛了
Father!
父亲！
Is this England?
嘿 这是英格兰吗？
We're in England?
我们到英格兰了？
You're completely wrong!
你完全错了！
These are the Faroe Islands.
这是法罗群岛
They're right between Iceland and Norway.
在冰岛和挪威正中间
We'll rest here to make the journey easier.
我们在这里休息 好让接下去的旅程轻松一点
There's a village in that fjord up ahead.
前面的峡湾里有个村子
We'll get drinking water there and I can sell my goods.
那里能弄到饮水 我还能卖我的东西
By the way, are you planning to come all the way to England with us?
对了 你是打算跟着我们 一路到英格兰吗？
Get ready to row!
准备好划桨！
All right, do your best!
好了 用尽全力！
I wish we didn't have to do this.
要是不用做这个就好了…
My butt hurts!
我的屁股好疼！
What's wrong, Leif?
雷夫 你怎么了？
Something's wrong.
情况有点不对劲
What is it?
什么不对劲？
That's what I'm wondering.
问题就在这里
Something different from last time.
和我之前来的时候不太一样
I know. It's the number of houses. There are fewer.
我知道了 是房屋的数量
Let's turn back, Leif. I have a bad feeling about this.
雷夫 那我们回去 我感觉不妙
The terrain's bad too.
地势也很不好
-What? -Are you serious?
-什么？ -你认真的？
Hey, they're rowing backwards.
嘿 他们往回倒了
Did they notice us?
他们看到我们了？
Not bad.
不错嘛
They're careful. They may prove to be formidable.
他们很小心 可能真的很难打败
They're too close, but it can't be helped.
他们太接近了 但也没办法
The ships will be slightly damaged, but do it!
船稍微损坏一点没关系 下手吧！
The fjord entrance is blocked!
峡湾入口被堵住了
Take that!
接着吧！
All right, excellent! They're just rats in a trap.
好了 很好！ 他们已经变成陷阱里的老鼠了
Thors! Everyone! Are you hurt?
托尔兹！所有人！你们都没事吧？
Everyone safe?
大家都没事吧？
-Yes! -More or less.
-没事 -基本上没事
Arrows will fall. Protect your heads!
会有箭射下来 保护头部！
Leif, what's your damage?
雷夫 你那边情况怎么样？
We're good. No damage to the ship or the crew.
我们没事 船和船员都没事
They're coming.
他们来了
The person who set this trap is further up the fjord.
布下陷阱的人在峡湾更深处
Further up?
更深处？
Pirates?
是海盗吗？
These are house pillars.
这些是房屋柱子
We're completely blocked in.
我们被彻底挡在这里了
They got us.
他们抓到了我们
They'll spare us if we surrender.
如果我们投降的话 能活命吗？
You don't know that!
这你可不能确定！
Of course not!
当然不能！
If we're caught, we'll just be sold as slaves. Brace yourselves!
如果我们被抓住 就会被当奴隶卖掉 准备好吧！
There are only two ships.
只有两艘船
Put it away, Ari.
亚雷 放下剑
They're skilled fighters.
他们是技术高超的打手
Farmers are no match for roaming pirates.
农民根本不是到处扫荡的海盗的对手
You don't stand a chance against them.
和他们打 你没有任何机会
Father.
父…父亲…
Thors?
托尔兹？
Thorfinn.
托尔芬
Only use this to protect yourself.
只有保护自己的时候才能用
Do you hear me? Only as a last resort.
听到了吗？紧要关头才能用
You're going to kill them after all?
你还是要杀了他们？
You are, aren't you?
是要杀的 对吧？
All right! Let's kill them!
好吧 我们来杀掉他们！
Don't say "kill" so easily.
别把“杀”说得这么轻飘飘
Bjorn! That mushroom…
表伦 那个蘑菇…
One, two, three… Eleven, twelve… and one kid.
一 二 三…十一 十二…还有一个孩子
What? That's all?
什么？就那么点人？
Hey, Askeladd!
嘿 阿谢拉特！
Could you let me handle this alone?
让我一个人处理 行吗？
It'll be no fun if we all go against so few.
大家一起杀这么几个人 太没意思了
I'll find out what kind of man this Troll of Jom is.
我倒要来看看 这个约姆的巨怪到底是怎么样一个人
Go ahead. It seems he wishes for the same.
去吧 看起来他也是这么希望的
Bastard!
混 混蛋！
What's with you?
你怎么回事？
Where did you fall from?
你是从哪里掉下来的？
Brother!
兄弟！
Let's kill him.
我们去杀了他
Not bad.
不错嘛
Troll of Jom.
约姆的巨怪